[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn have better
conversations with ourselves
howdy duty radiator springs it's me
lightning mcqueen the host of the
junkyard love podcast i'm super happy
you're here
today is day four of sober october for
me uh
i'm rocking it with my homies a few
people been on the podcast brandon cruz
zack wilde
uh nasty nate matt young i got a couple
other homies the next episode with uh
connor ann shoes he's on it too uh shout
out to everybody who's participating in
whatever your version of sober october
is i think the point is just to
get a little handle on our habits right
you know we're just a ball of
habits we just do the same things all
the time and when you want to
step into your future self and and feed
the future you
rather than the right now you really
beautiful things can happen so
day four i'm feeling pretty good i wish
i had some coffee we're doing no
caffeine
uh i've got no caffeine no alcohol no
masturbation
and no weed so i'm not sleeping super
well the caffeine would help but
i'm gonna be just fine i'm gonna be all
right i'm not gonna die
everything's good and i just want to
wish that to anybody else
who's going through their version of
sober october if you want to start your
own version
there's just do it pick a friend don't
pick a friend put some dates on your
calendar and just stick
to it just do your thing two weeks of
no notifications going to your phone uh
one week of trying to sleep on your back
rather than on your stomach
uh doing five minutes with stretches
before bed for
14 days whatever it is in your life try
to drink
gallon of gallon of water a day or maybe
a cup of water a day if you don't drink
any water which is ridiculous you should
drink more water
just set some goals for yourself
if if you don't have anything right now
i mean covet is kicking our asses man
don't don't let it keep kicking your ass
if you've got
some boundaries that you want to set if
you've got some structure that you need
to build for yourself
i'm just i'm just here with my friends
you know to say
you got this you can do it stick to it
you can do this let's get rolling with
the podcast
i'm super happy y'all here today it's
with anna cantwell
she is just wonderful everything about
the mind
everything about the spirit everything
about
self-love mindfulness she's a coach
she's a meditation teacher she's a yoga
instructor
uh she taught writing she's taught young
children
dude just super blessed to have her on
today um
crazy amounts of golden fantastic
nuggets
in this podcast i'm on social i'm not on
social media right now
so if you did enjoy this episode if you
enjoyed maybe a clip of it if you
enjoyed just some of it whatever
if you could share on your social media
or just send to a friend
whatever whatever the more people that
uh we can help with these
fantastically wonderful conversations
the better you know so
take care of yourselves challenge
yourself a little bit
set a goal and stick to it you got this
let's go
anna hello hi jake
how are you i uh i'm doing swell i woke
up to
the most beautiful sunrise probably one
of the most beautiful i've ever seen in
my whole life and
it was a whole moment so i'm feeling
really good that sounds amazing was it
uh was it tinted like red
or orange because of the the smoke is
there any smoke over where you're at
there was the past couple of days but
not so much today
i will say a few days ago it was
totally gray and then the sun was just
this
bright like pink orange orb
it looks like you know a hole in the sky
it makes you feel like you're in the
truman hill or something
right very very star wars
kind of ask really cool and then also
you know it's it's mixed feelings right
there's these fires ablaze
and then you're also seeing this
beautiful you know byproduct of it
right yeah i feel like it's almost when
you see uh
like a red sun or a red moon or any of
those things like when it's fire you're
like i
do i feel guilty about saying that's
beautiful in a strange way
yes absolutely it's so that's such a
funny
um i don't know such a funny concept
paradoxical
yeah i mean that's that's the thing
about knowledge though once you like you
could see it like wow that's just
mesmerizing but then once you learn the
knowledge of it being
painful for other people it's like oh i
don't know what to feel now
but um yeah overall beautiful i was just
i was down in um
like reading lake shasta for a few days
and uh
yeah i love it there we go on vacation
fairly often down there um
and in the mornings it was just like i'd
get up to go on my run
and it's like oh it's smoky but then you
just see this the craziest red
morning sun ever and so it's just it's
distracting and mesmerizing and
wonderful
but uh i'm i'm back home now and it's
kind of just muggy and there's a little
bit of smoke in the air
it seems like the fires are somewhat
getting under control
so that's always good to hear um anna
so let's uh let's tell people of the
junkyard love podcast the listeners
so we actually got linked up through
your friend chase i've worked with chase
before
um he's a good guy he's a stud he just
worked on the
the david blaine's ascension did you see
that oh my gosh
it's like up but to the eighth degree
yes really really just beautiful
beautiful and badass and strangely
hopeful
yeah i feel like that blind blow through
the sky just thousands of feet up with
these big colorful balloons
i love he was talking about i watched
him on the joe rogan podcast and he was
talking about how
he really wanted that image like he
didn't want like a visible giant visible
harness from a distance he didn't want
like a bunch of like stuff showing like
they have a couple
like gopros and stuff you can kind of
see but he really just wanted that
like that still shot of just holding one
hand on i just thought that was so cool
i'm like dude you're such an artist you
know he's a magician but he's really
an artist truthfully like creating
something that only he has done
oh my gosh and what and what an
experience i was talking to
a friend about it and it was just a nice
you know not to him small but to in the
grand scheme of things a small
symbol of hope for the time i thought
that was a beautiful interpretation
indeed yeah and then i mean the fact
that chase was working on it i mean he's
he's one of the best i've worked with
him on a couple shows i've worked with
him uh
on a few student student organizations
years ago and then we've actually worked
together on like a hernia society
like some hernia conference at some
point so we have like funny stories
together but um
great guy it's it's super cool that that
we got linked up um i love that
this podcast seems to just like it just
connects me with people that i never
thought that i would
have the opportunity to connect to and
uh it's just like
it's really great you know we can talk
about synchronicities later but
those are those are what i like to
sprinkle on i'm like well hey this came
up and it's i'm not expecting it but i
think that i need to say yes to it you
know that's that's how i've been feeling
i love it and it's such it's a beautiful
beautiful
web because i feel like you know the
conversations that chase and i
already have are so just podcast level
i'm like
this is awesome just talking about some
of the most
rich and beautiful deep concepts in all
of the universe
and the fun stuff like synchronicities
like
last night so i just for context
i recently moved to joshua tree from la
so out into
the high desert and for a myriad of
reasons
and just really looking for some
spaciousness and deeper connection to
nature
it's really important to me and i had
one of those you know those things for
your car
that reflect the sun so it doesn't get
you know hot as hell
um that was in our house and i was like
oh i should go put this in the car right
now
so i took it out last night to put it in
the car and the second that i stepped
out
i looked up into the sky and i saw
the most beautiful longest
shooting star i have ever seen
i was just sitting there mouth a gape
just just dumbfounded completely
astounded as it just
travels it felt like it traveled so far
and then just
hung there just saying hey girl
it's gonna be all right yeah wow dude
that's great you know what's funny i
feel like i always have like a
i'm whenever i'm looking at the stars
i'm always enjoying it but there's a
thing in the back of my mind i'm like
man i wish one of us was shooting right
now it'd be cool to see
like you're always like kind of wishing
for it but then that's the thing is
you're just like you just went outside
to go
get a sunscreen thing and you look up
and of course there it is
and also isn't it crazy to think of the
science behind like
when you see a shooting star you know
it's like
billions of years old or like it's isn't
happening anywhere near the same time
frame as you that's just mind-blowing
yes and someone recently told me that
it's it's like frozen and it's the water
that's burning off through i don't know
i didn't fully understand it and i don't
need to fully understand
it appreciate it
yeah it's amazing it's just it's so
funny how you know we could be so
complicated creatures but then also
things like a shooting star or just the
stars or a waterfall we're just like
oh amazing just get lost in it you know
it's so great
totally and this is it's a concept that
i love that uh
eckhart tolle talks about a lot that
things like
flowers things like crystals are
such beautiful representations of
enlightenment
because you know they have sure
some purpose right pollination whatever
but
in general flowers pretty crystals
they're just beautiful they're just
absolutely beautiful and
the fact that we get something from
admiring them
just because they're beautiful not
because any you know anyone or anything
really made them that way they just
are and that brings us to a space of
enlightenment
just by being able to appreciate
beauty for beauty sake yeah totally
i like to uh my like i went on my run
this morning
and uh what i like to do there's this
cut out towards like the the beginning
of our town
and it's this i mean i think it's over a
hundred years
i touch it all the time i should know
but i think it's over 100 years old they
took like this big stump and they put it
sideways
and they put like on the rings like what
year it was you know like 1917 1924
you know um as exact as they could i'm
sure but like just seeing that um
you know something there's something
about beauty that
also reminds you of your insignificance
like at the same time you know that
sounds kind of it's not supposed to be
depressing or sad but it really is like
oh yeah i am only here for a minute
amount of time
you know like you you feel uh i had
another podcast guess a life coach
actually as well uh and she
she loves saying take me somewhere where
i feel small
rebecca wilde was her name yeah and i
feel like when you
when you see things that make you feel
small and significant there is a beauty
in that
like this it's like a reminder that you
don't know anything and that's okay
in a way you know oh it's so funny this
morning
at the breakfast table we were talking
about insignificance and
and the idea that oh this is so
depressing to be so
insignificant and i said no it's not at
all
it's oddly relieving to feel that you
know what
i ca as much meaning as i love to infuse
into life
and purpose and passion like all of that
is wonderful
and my life in the grand scheme
is about as long as that shooting star
that i saw
and that's okay it's wonderful in fact
yeah it makes it that much more um
special somehow i mean yeah we have the
ability as humans to give things power
in that manner but i feel like even
before we give them power
there's just this knowing of of the
power that it holds just
being kind of in the structure of time
itself
um so i want to
i want to give the listeners a little
bit of your background so you can start
as far as you'd like you're in joshua
tree now
um but you know i want to talk about
your your journey with your spiritual
awakening i want to talk about yoga i
want to talk about meditation
uh where does it feel like it starts for
you
december 10 1992
i was born um no
i am one of those people who just the
sense
that i have my felt sense is that i was
so to speak born with my third eye open
meaning this that i was very naturally
attuned to
the spiritual realm i always
as early as i can remember felt deep
deep empathy
felt deep deep connection with nature
felt that kind of awe and enlightenment
that's so
needed to see beyond just our
little boxes and our little spheres you
know what i mean
the bigger picture and i felt i remember
just feeling
in the wind i feel spirit when i'm
swinging on the swing set at recess i'm
matching my breath and i'm constructing
universes
in the clouds that was me as a child
and i wasn't it wasn't like i was some
buddha
because pretty soon i found out that i
had anxiety
and i had this also highly
active that's how i like to call it
highly active
mind that for a long time
went and jumped to i would say somewhere
around like eight or nine years old kind
of when the pure
the pure innocence of childhood really
starts to fade away
that i felt this internal
anxiety this pressure this
what if this horrible thing happens and
my imagination kind of
um spun out i guess
and it wasn't like i had any i had a
beautiful childhood i had a ton of time
too and i'm so grateful for it
to play outside in nature i was in
nature a lot
i was reading a ton and and part of that
really like i said it grew my
imagination
it grew my perspective i read so much
that i feel
it really gave me kind of a
head start on putting myself in other
people's shoes
you were reading like right around the
age of nine like like are you talking
right after that or
oh yeah just i mean reading is as early
as i can remember
i feel like i was reading books at you
know
small books at six and i love i love
reading as well
oh it's like it's the best i remember
reading
um you know things like lord of the
rings in like fourth grade
and just so weird i literally read that
i
okay i feel i know i'm already
interrupting you on your story i'm sorry
anna but i feel like as you're speaking
of these things so i was born a few
months before you
i felt similar i always felt very black
sheep um and then around when i was
around eight or nine i had like that's
when my like life trauma like my family
things started happening
and so it like opened me up to this
whole different version of myself and i
started experiencing anxiety and those
sort of things as well
super crazy and i literally read lord of
the rings i don't think it was in fourth
grade but it was somewhere around there
but
yeah so um yeah continue going so you're
reading you're going through this
experience you're
experiencing anxiety totally so i'm
you know as as school does and i feel
like i can also speak to this because i
was a school teacher
as well um that you know
it's it's about deadlines it's about
getting it right
and not necessarily learning so i really
took to that
i was like okay we want to get it right
let's get it right
and you want to be the smart kid okay
let's study as much as we can
read as much as we can be very much kind
of the like good girl
archetype teacher's pet and and coming
from you know part of it's coming from a
pure place
part of it's coming from what i believe
is my kind of intrinsic
motivation i've always been
intrinsically motivated
but then of course i wanted as our
little egos do
to look smart and be smart and
that kind of became my identity and that
is a really
delicate thing to try to uphold when
you're spinning lots of plates
and you are trying to just
hold on or grasp on to a certain
identity
whatever it is if it's the top you know
you want to be the best athlete or you
want to be
the most extroverted or the performer or
whatever it
is mine was like school getting it right
so i worked really hard
and i had all of this chronic stomach
pain
it was so interesting to see the direct
correlation
between the pressure that i was putting
on myself
because i'll admit fully there wasn't a
ton of external pressure
it was some a lot of it was
internal pressure and then some of it
is just the expectation that the people
in our family are high performers so
this is nothing exceptional this is just
expected
right and that really
it bread in me a lot of a lot of fear
of making mistakes and that
inhibited what my true nature my true
essence desired which is learning
i was always so curious and i just
wanted to learn
as much as i could about as many things
as i could
of course some some subjects interested
me more than others
however i just that insatiable curiosity
was really hindered by this
gripping of identity trying to get it
right
trying to are or needing to always be
the best
not my best right or not the best
with my mental and physical health still
intact
so really after that i
i went to college i you know i went from
being like big fish in a little pond i
grew up in tennessee
and you know with the
beautiful nature and connection to
animals and all of that
also came some some small-mindedness
right and was really religious
and followed that really strictly too
because that's another thing
you can get right and you can check the
boxes and you can be accepted
and belong and it's it's not all coming
from that of course
however there was really a part of me
too that loved just the exploratory
nature
the inquiry and i realized that what i
do now
is so similar to what i was doing
then when i was as young as i can
remember
seriously like third grade fourth grade
i was leading small groups of people and
studying the bible
and journaling through that and asking
questions
and using it to reflect and that's
a lot of what i do now just not
necessarily with the bible
i think the bible is a beautiful text
has tons of truth and wisdom to glean
and it's not necessarily the full
picture right so once i went to college
things
really really opened up however
um i don't remember who says this is a
pretty
famous one there's no coming to
consciousness except through pain
i don't i know yeah you want some like
some cold truth for like high school
truth first thing in the morning
that's fun and it's i i don't believe it
fully i think that there are lots of
ways of
which you can come to self-awareness and
consciousness but pain is certainly one
of them and it's certainly an effective
one
so i describe my time in college as
getting kind of like body slammed by the
universe
just like smackdown of trauma
i experienced several instances
of sexual trauma in college that
left me absolutely reeling of course
that didn't help the anxiety which now
is like
fully spun out into fear and paranoia
it didn't you know it really brought on
depression
and just sadness and i
you know i was working several jobs all
throughout college to
pay my way and had to kind of scale back
on everything
because my mental health was in such a
tough place and that was a
huge wake-up call for me
that that really has to come first
during that time i love that you've
already been talking about your runs
going on runs in the morning there was a
time when
i really it was like you struggle to get
out of bed every day
you know it's like that's a that's a
feat and
i told myself okay there has to be there
has to be one thing
that you do every single day that's just
one thing
and that thing was running and it's
funny now because i don't even really
i only run now and then
i just what i would do is every morning
7 15
feet hit the floor put your clothes on
just get outside to start going
just doesn't have to be fast like there
i didn't put a time limit on myself it
was just like go for a run
once a day and i found this
hill in this neighborhood this huge hill
that i could run down so that i would
have to run up it
i didn't have an option and
i would listen to this is also a
beautiful synchronicity
i would listen to roar by katy perry
on repeat i wouldn't dislike
that was my anthem it was to me it was
so much about having your voice
heard and in my experiences i felt like
my voice was
taken away and that i didn't get that
chance to speak up for myself
and that's what that song meant to me
and that's what running up this
huge ass hill every morning meant to me
and this beautiful synchronicity that i
have to share
is that i found out years years later
that chase produced the production
of roar that was underneath the brooklyn
bridge that was like this
epic thing and then way af
way after that because i didn't even
know chase then years later
i wrote down in a journal one night man
i'd really like to see
katy perry i would love to see katy
perry in concert she inspired me so much
this song got me through this tough time
and the next day
chase calls me up and said hey
oh yes yes way he says hey
they're doing this show after her tour
her tour had ended it was two weeks
after
doing this random pop-up show at the ace
hotel in los
angeles and he said do you want to come
with me it's it's vip
tickets i said i guess yeah
i think that sounds great so
wild wild wild how those little
pieces get kind of woven through our
lives but
at that time literally that song that
hill was my saving grace and if i could
do that in a day i said okay
that's that's a sign i'm still alive
we're still breathing
like i can take one more step forward i
can
do this for one more day and then it
became
you know i fought kind of legal battles
around this to try and seek some justice
and that was a really
necessary albeit highly re-traumatizing
step in the process to try to
face those fears and not not run from
them
so i felt like i really needed to do
this
and it was a long process it was a
highly
painful process it was an expensive
process
and at the end of it you know
it's very rare that those kinds of
cases end up going the way that you'd
like them to
and even if they do you know what what
do you have then
right it's really it's really tough
and so when i finished that it was right
around when i was graduating
and i decided you know what i've done
what i can
to do this i faced up to these fears
i have you know i've leaned into at this
time i was doing
a lot of yoga i was doing a lot of zumba
just things to help me
get back into my body because that's
another
you know side effect of course is like
this disassociation from your body
and i just said i have to leave this
battle here who who really wins
if you know these people are on living
their lives
and i'm here with you know depressed and
anxious and all of this
so it was like okay the best thing that
i can do
is live a [__] awesome life that
best thing that i can do oh yeah yeah
that's so powerful
i mean because like what is winning in
that situation you know such a
i can't even imagine like that's the
question what what
is winning and and if this if this thing
goes this way or if
x person's life is now ruined is that
is that winning like is it is it winning
if
you know you it's it's a it's a really
good question
justice is a strange thing and uh yeah
i'm sure
you you know that very well that's so
crazy um
it's it's super cool that you uh went
through the yoga journey too we'll
definitely get into that because
i'm uh i began my disassociation journey
when i was young
and i didn't learn about it until like
three years ago
uh when i started two years ago or
whatever when i started doing my own
yoga and learn
anything about anything um wow that's so
crazy okay uh
continue carry on so so after the the
court stuff has
has fizzled out you've still been doing
some yoga are you still in school after
this or
was this after that was right when i it
kind of coincided with my graduation
and i felt like okay let's leave i was
going to school in north carolina i said
let's leave this
here and you know what i had felt really
passionate about what was
always my path was education
psychology how do people learn i have
learned a lot about positive psychology
and
a thesis that i had written was on
optimism
and how people who are optimistic
actually
go bigger are healthier
make more money are better leaders all
this
incredible research on
positive psychology and you know i was
all throughout college i was
volunteering in schools and
you know because of my christian
background
and my parents are very much um
you know they're very service oriented
they have a non-profit i was always
attuned to service and i felt like
yes this is service is a beautiful lens
through which to live right how can i
waking up every day saying how can i
serve
right what can i give and so i took that
and decided to become a teacher
i became a school teacher i went to
i saw this program it was a master's
program in houston and i thought
all right let's try it on and see how
this goes
and that i think the distance
and just being in a new place is really
helpful
for people that have been through
something traumatic because
especially when it's really associated
with a particular place
it's like constant reminders so i was
like i gotta give myself
a fighting chance to really powerfully
move forward and while this was a really
this was a huge step it was still
really really tough i was teaching
at a charter school in northeast houston
i was 22. i was in grad school full-time
as well i was living on my own for the
first time you know
outside of college and it was it was
just
really really tough you know the
resources that you have available in
schools
the pay and fighting for you know
some kind of livable fair way
for doing this work and and it's so
funny because when i reflect on that
time
it was never the kids the kids are never
the problem
the kids are far and away
a their kids so they're just learning
and figuring out
so much and they're doing the absolute
best that they can right i had
what i really grappled with on a daily
basis was the overarching
system and the structure and saying is
this something that
you know no matter how well my cog is
working
what is this machine doing right what
what are we teaching
them overall like what are the subjects
even are these the most important
subjects
what else could we be teaching them at
this like pivotal age you know
oh my gosh and then just getting that
like
this is it's so like the long-term
investment thing
to me is is the
the issue with education is that this is
the this is our future
right so it makes so much sense to
really invest in it
and it seems like the first thing that
at least
in america that we kind of skimp on is
the education of our youth so
it was it was really tough and i felt
like i started to just get to a point
where
i was so stressed you know at this point
my chronic
pain is is flaring there's a lot of also
kind of toxic habits that you pick up in
an environment where
so many people who have really good
hearts right teachers or
they are there because they want to
serve are just trying to cope
and so there's there's complaining
there's
drinking there's just trying to vent to
just
try to relieve some of the weight and
the pressure that you feel
of growing the youth and so
i'm like the hardest job ever yeah i'm
totally with you like i i
when i see teachers like regardless if
you're teaching like i don't even know
any age really i just i have friends who
are school counselors now and stuff
and i'm just like i don't like i when i
was these those kids as ages i would
have never listened to you unfortunately
like and so i just like working with
such a strange situation
really just a teachers are the best
example of
like working with what they have i guess
like doing the best
that they can with what they have you
know we have such a weird structure that
i really wish that we were teaching a
lot of different things i hopefully
i'm optimistic that we'll lean towards
that way in the coming years but
yeah and that's well that's a beautiful
kind of next
step because there was a teacher at my
school who
got to teach yoga to kids during the day
and i thought that was the coolest
thing so i started to connect with her
and of course the kids
love it it's getting them into their
bodies it's teaching them
how to handle the emotions that are
going
bonkers at that age and like
realistically all ages
that you know it's teaching them
emotional regulation they're reading
books like the four agreements and i'm
like god if i had read that in high
school i like to
i'd like to think that i would have
taken to it but maybe not
right yeah it's hard to say and she
really inspired me at this time
truly my saving grace was yoga
and i was going to this yoga studio that
a fellow teacher of mine recommended
that had wonderful programming
was these 40 day challenges where really
the goal was
to get super consistent in your practice
and then we have these weekly meetings
where you come together
and really just dive into personal
development
and self-inquiry it's where i first
started to learn about meditation
and god was i a bad meditator at this
time
i cuz my mind it just goes quick
and there's nothing wrong with that
right i think when we start to think
like
oh that's bad or wrong i'm kind of
joking about the bad meditation yeah i
know
yeah but i couldn't sit still for five
minutes without just throwing my hands
in the air
however and i and i really didn't get it
at first so if you're listening
to this and you're like i so don't get
meditation
i hear you i was literally there
i was like how does sitting still help
me
how you know right i have friends who
i'm just gonna like stop this part and
send it like hey start right here
just listen to this because i have so
many because i because meditation is new
for me over the last few years and i'm
always you know
i'm in my preachy stage of it really i'm
always trying to get everybody to try it
i'm like you gotta try
and uh it's it's such a strange concept
um and it sucks but like you you just
don't
truly understand at the beginning and
that's kind of discouraging to hear
but i think that like once you if you
can keep building the habit or you can
keep trying keep trying to learn
knowledge about it
there is aha moments there is things
that click and you're like oh
i did just do the meditation like just
because i'm not
uh enlightened all of a sudden doesn't
mean that i didn't just do the
meditation
you know totally you don't have to be a
you know you don't have to be floating
you don't have to have some crazy
transcendental experience
it's really plenty to breathe
such that your nervous system shifts
into the parasympathetic
because we are so often living we're
just
living in fight or flight and it's
because of these things
there's so much of it alerts
alarms all of that it's making us feel
like
think about if every second of the day
you
felt like a tiger was chasing you this
is the proverbial
tiger right is chasing you every second
that's exhausting it's no wonder that
people develop
chronic illnesses that people have
adrenal fatigue
all you know autoimmune disorder all of
these
you know different implications from
just high high levels of stress
that has little to no reprieve is
horrifying to me oh my gosh
so what what clicked for me anna with
with um i mean there's i had a lot of
crazy moments with meditation it's been
such a beautiful thing for my life but
um what you were just saying about you
know looking out for for a lion or a
tiger
um is i had read this book i think it's
emily fletcher with ziva meditation or
z technique um but she had talked it was
something that really stuck out to me is
like
do you really think that your body which
is made to like survive and thrive and
we're like these wonderful living
biological creatures who are like the
top of the food chain we've like
grown out of the food chain at this
point but
uh basically she was saying when you see
a lion or you're like oh what is that
brown spot over there
is that a lion am i about to die do i
need to run your fingernails are like
let's not choose right now to grow let's
send that blood to other places of the
body let's
think other thoughts like so when you're
we're basically like biologically built
to survive
and then now we have this life over the
last i mean not even
100 years that's just changed so much
um and and now we're we're dealing with
things of like
you know i get a notification on my
phone that does the exact equivalent
of me seeing a lion under the corner of
my eye
so our bodies are in these states of
like your fingernails are not growing
your immune system has just shut down
um i'm sure it's correlated to
inflammation
all of these things i think that when i
had heard that i was like oh gosh
that does kind of make sense and then i
would really start to think of man i do
kind of get triggered by my phone i do
get triggered quickly by things and when
you're triggered or it's
um you're you know we've all felt
anxiety we've all felt like that sudden
sweat
that sudden like uncomfortable you read
something you don't like you just hear
some bad news whatever it is
that part that like wakes up in your
body is is nothing to be ashamed of
but it is what we're dealing with right
it's the biological
truth of what we are yeah so yeah
so continue going on meditation i really
any other advice you have for beginner
meditators
i'm always like hey guys listen to this
part oh my gosh
there's so many things that i could say
one thing that i really
want to harp on about the stress
response
is that your digestion stops
right you're trying to run away from
something digesting food doesn't mean
[__]
let's not poop right now let's not do it
yeah we're not doing that right now
right and so it's it's
to me that was a huge source of my
stomach pain and that when i really
learned how to
regulate my breath throughout the day
take deeper breaths throughout the day
that
absolutely completely
eliminated my chronic pain really breath
meditation and cannabis for pain
management
was got rid of it entirely from
going from people saying you will be in
pain for the rest of your life
without a doubt i think a lot of people
have heard that a lot
from their doctors because because they
don't know they're at the edge of what
their abilities are in in the
you know nothing against doctors at all
but where i think there's so many
doctors who are in a place of like it's
anxiety i just don't
really know like you gotta figure that
out however you figure that out
they're like i don't know anxiety i'm
sorry totally and it and
it's okay that it's not in their their
wheelhouse right so
we find other other ways to cope and to
me
you look at anyone who is a you know
high performer super successful they
will
all tell you number one thing meditate
truly it is the
simplest just lowest hanging fruit
to begin to cultivate a healthy
mental state that will also because this
is something i love
to discuss is that will also affect
your body and your spirit it it never
will just
target one part of it of course it's an
incredible thing to have a healthy mind
to have a resilient mind
to know when and be able to metacognate
right
to see oh i'm thinking about this thing
what is that why am i thinking this way
about this thing is this just a very
familiar
pattern is this just the path i've gone
down again and again so it feels
safe it feels comfortable is there
another path
one of my favorite questions and this
this applies for
new meditators is am i willing
to see this differently am i willing to
see this
scenario in another way am i willing to
see meditation
in another way a lot of people i think
they just think that it's just sitting
there
and there's one element sure that is
there's also
a lot of ways to meditate i love for my
people who just like
they're just moving all the time they
gotta be moving
walking meditation a lovely lovely
practice that
cultivates mindfulness and
while i do think the sit i think this
sid is crucial
walking meditation is a beautiful way
where you can just start to notice
how does it feel when my feet hit the
floor what is it like to move through
space without needing to land at a
destination
just that simple process is enough
to take us from fight or flight to rest
and digest to parasympathetic nervous
system
and that's enough just to give our our
vagus nerve
right responsible stress response just
right it gives it that relaxation
because otherwise it's just clenched and
tight
all the time imagine i don't remember
where i read this but
imagine trying to like grow your biceps
just by flexing your bicep constantly
like that's insanity
that's not how it works that rest as
well i mean
a lot of times when we're working out i
used to be a big gym guy when
we're working out you're kind of like
tearing it you're tearing the muscle and
then
it heals when you let it heal when you
stop moving it
but if you never put that thing down
like that that muscle is not going to do
what it's good what it's meant to do
grow man that's it that's so great that
you mentioned
i'm loving everything that you mentioned
there when it comes to meditation um
with walking meditation
for me a walking meditation didn't click
too much for me i had to do quite a bit
of
sitting and i used a lot of what did get
me to click
a lot of my meditation was sam harris's
waking up app
i don't know if you checked that one out
but that was when i did the walking
meditation on there and i realized
it's actually a profound moment i think
for a lot of people to realize like wait
i'm never walking like this like
whenever you're
walking anywhere it's to a destination
and life is not
about getting from here there it's the
walk in between like that's the moments
of your life right
alan watts says life is um or a dance is
not
getting from one end of the room to the
other the fastest it's the dance in
between you know
um and and so for me
it was so so it started clicking
you know when you just so i was doing
guided meditations which
listener guided meditations are awesome
they're so great like don't think like i
can't do without a meditation
without an app whatever like do it for
years with an app if that's what you
need you know get get the knowledge in
your brain and get some experience and
don't
you know there's no rush here um but uh
so when you're when you're walking i
i it was like you the meditator or the
the guided meditator would say you know
feel
every part of your feet right like feel
the moment that you are about to lift it
up and the moment your heel lifts up and
it's all these slow-motion kind of
moments
and you'll feel this urge to like why am
i doing this like i wanna what am i
doing i need to do something i need to
go i need it
like you need to assign yourself a task
but then you it's this hilarious moment
almost when you're like oh yeah this
is the thing and and then when you add
up the
it's a little difficult at the beginning
i think with meditation to see how it
quantifies
but that's where things like and i'm
sure you can attest to this
um things like hope and faith you know i
i used to um
i i've talked about this before like i i
haven't been
uh spirituality is a new thing for me
like probably two or three years ago
but when i was younger i just wouldn't
really like listen to anything like
religious or
like the words hope and faith are in our
culture
tied in with a lot of christian religion
i feel
and so for me as like i'm just the cool
rebel guy
like i don't mess with that religion
stuff it ain't for me so when i even
hear the words faith and hope or
whatever
i throw the baby out the it bathwater
yeah so so like reintroducing these
things and allowing like uh
allowing myself to take a second look at
like wait what what does hope mean does
it mean what i actually think it means
like or why don't i look up the
definition and really
take it apart from the things that i
apparently don't like and see what it
means to me so
with i just want to say any listener
have hope
and have faith like if you're going to
start this this journey you don't have
to worry about the whole journey just
think right now just
if there's a voice in your head that's
like this is ridiculous just try a
little bit of faith try
try like you know this this is gonna
help you it's hard to know how it's
gonna help you at this moment but
have a little faith yeah oh absolutely
and i love
you know hope i did also some research
on on
hope when i was in college and
the base definition of hope is
seeing a more positive outcome and
multiple pathways
to that positive outcome right so it's
just acknowledging
this could be better something could be
better than how i perceive it to be
right now
and that there's not just one way of
getting there
and that's i will always that's a tenet
of
how i coach of everything that i do
which is it's a multi-pronged approach
for me i needed god knows i mean for a
long time it was therapy and
so much therapy i've pretty much been in
therapy since i was
15 14 and almost straight through
probably for like 10 years and then for
a long time
it was yoga meditation breath work
essential oils plant medicine journaling
mentors coach it like you name it
it's there right and that it's it's
really the
coming together of all of these
different aspects so
and you get to choose that for yourself
now what i will say about meditation
i believe that meditation that the quiet
time
especially because of our world today
how it is
just the reality of the world that we
live in we so
rarely get entirely quiet
time without the information or opinion
of
anyone else that if you want to
learn your authentic self if you want to
be more of yourself
then and if you want to connect really
to the part of you that is connected to
everything you got to spend some quiet
time
alone like although as alone as you can
be
and it doesn't have to be an hour
i always like to tell people you know i
meditate
an hour a day because this is my full
this is my whole deal
this is what i do i show up for a lot of
people
on a daily basis in programs and
one-on-one
so that my number one job is to be as
clear of a vessel for spirit to flow
through
as possible and to me that means
a lot of times pretty much every day i
meditate an hour
however if you have five minutes that is
worth
something it's it's for you
never comparing comparing is one of the
silliest
things that we do it really makes no
sense when you think about it why would
i ever compare myself
to someone who hasn't had the lived
experience
or the dna or the childhood
or the you know all of that stuff to
get you to where you are on your journey
right now
we all have our paths it's a beautiful
thing
own where your journey begins some
people
they they get to this at 70.
some people they get to this at seven
and it's really it's just a beautiful
thing to know that
there are countless ways to that better
place
for you for you yourself
and the last thing i'll say that's like
this totally changed my perspective of
meditation
which is you only do a certain number of
things every day
right most of us we probably
eat maybe we shower we sleep every day
you know we go to the bathroom these
kinds of things
and meditation is like
doing any of those things it's like
showering
for your brain it's just that daily
process that we require to keep our
brains
healthy our mind our mental state
healthy and so it's not like oh if i
accumulate
enough meditation points i'll get to
stop meditating
i only ever only ever meditated
more as i have become more peaceful
more myself all of these things so even
though i'm
blessed enough that there's not a whole
lot of stress
in my life because i've made a lot of
choices to design my life that way where
i
get to meditate an hour a day and i get
to do
all the yoga that i need and i get to go
on walks and hikes and these things that
i love and that really feed my soul
that i only meditate more
more and more yeah i love that i i
uh it's funny it's funny seeing with my
journey on meditation seeing how i go
i mean i always so i made the habit
quickly i was lucky enough to make the
habit because i was just so obsessed
with it immediately i was like this is
the craziest thing like
because i was a i mean i i would say
like i was a sufferer of my own mind i
didn't realize that i wasn't my thoughts
right like i like i also had like a
creative fast adhd mind
and i like thought that i thought that
it was just
being in a stranglehold the rest of my
life and trying to like
don't say that say that don't say that
what you know like just confused by my
own brain but
um yeah meditation is just so i i do
at least 10 minutes a day um but it's
it's cool because it's it's just this
like thing just like you were saying was
showering and brushing your teeth
it's not like i have like a giant ritual
where i put on my
like orange monk robe and all these
things you know i think when we hear
meditation or any of those
mindfulness even we kind of accidentally
um
or just because we that's what we have
learned the little we have learned we
think of
this thing that has nothing to do with
us we're like this what
that has nothing to do that's not what
i'm into but it's you have a mind you
know you have
you have doesn't it's it's just a
beautiful thing um i
i want to just just right before you
continue going with your story
um can you give me your definition of
mindfulness
oh goodness this is this is always the
question
and i love it because there are
i mean there are as many definitions of
mindfulness
out there as there are people that have
ever
meditated to me
i try to keep it as simple as possible
that mindfulness
is present moment awareness
through a gentle lens through a
compassionate lens
it's being here now
and loving the moment
that's it simple as that so when people
say
am i meditating am i doing this right
it's it's as simple as that can you can
you remain
here when the mind wanders as it does as
it loves to do as it's designed to do
can you consciously draw it back
here draw it into the breath
and love the breath love
this moment wherever you are and
obviously
in some moments much easier said than
done
to love the moment and that's why
things like yoga are so helpful with
mindfulness
because you're in this uncomfortable
pose right you're
in this you're in this one posture
that might be really difficult for you
you look over and someone else ah
they're doing it so
easy and how do they get there and i
want to be there
instead of just breathing with it
instead of just softening into that
moment
and accepting and loving this is where i
am at
this is my body right now
and i love it that's amazing i really
like your definition of mindfulness i
think that's so perfect i the
the differences in um just
just from doing any amount of yoga i
feel like the difference is we notice
like oh geez i didn't even know that i
was breathing from my chest in my mouth
every day of all the time like you just
just even when you when they say focus
on your breath
in in papasana or yoga it's really
it's almost like your mind always needs
a little something and you're like hey
just listen to the breath then i know
you want to be thinking but
let's just try to focus on the breath
and a lot of times um
and and you can correct me with your
definitions if i'm
um not saying the same thing that you
think but uh
for me i try to notice the you know the
present moment is
for me it's a lot about my five senses
like you mentioned dissociation before
um and i had like i said i had so much
association that i didn't even like
really
know what it was i had began at a very
young age
um i had some even before
when i was nine i had some some trauma
that i experienced and i i think that's
uh when i learned to dissociate
and so when i learned that i was
dissociating a lot of times it's like
uh when you focus on your breath you
know like where do you feel your breath
is it at the tips of your nose
is it in your belly um you could feel
all these small
micro areas and there's almost this
just just multiple times of just like
this silliness that you kind of notice
when you're in
breathing in meditation or yoga where
you're just like oh my gosh like this is
this is the thing right like this is
what i'm supposed to be
i don't have to think of those thoughts
whatever my my mind was trying to tell
me to think about right now
it is so okay and rather important
to just feel what is my body doing what
does it feel like when i breathe and
yoga um oh man because because with yoga
if you've never done yoga listener it's
it's you move with your breath
you and and time is different in yoga i
feel like
it's it's it's just mind-blowing um i
did
um i did yoga with adrian on youtube if
you've ever i'm sure you've heard of her
anna um
yeah i just did she's one of my
favorites that's what got me into
into yoga actually or like actually
doing it consistently rather
but i did one of hers this morning so
yeah listener yoga we're going to keep
talking about it but
just go on youtube to start like just
just do anything just get going or even
just
lay on the ground for five minutes and
just start stretching around or you
mentioned cannabis
cannabis totally got me like if if you
smoke a decent amount of weed
you realize that stretching after you
smoke weed it feels so great
just add a little breath work on time
and you're going to have a wonderful
you're going to be like wow it's been an
hour and my body feels just crazy alive
right now i just stretched
yeah it's the best and that was that was
another one of my
kind of saving graces when i was a
school teacher
i thought okay when i wasn't going to
the studio because a lot of times i was
going to the studio and this just
happened to be
power vinyasa super heated
yoga and in houston like double heated
yoga
so it was definitely not the best to be
high at
however you it was totally like high on
your own supply
kind of yoga and super sweaty and i
needed at that time
something really intense to capture
my attention and keep me present that's
really good for that
now i prefer a much different style of
yoga
much more breath centric build your own
heat
kind of practice and really you know
attuning
and listening to your body for what it
is that you need that day
maybe sometimes you do want to just end
up
you know flat in a puddle of your own
sweat and that's
awesome and that's what you need that
day and then other times
maybe you need some restorative yoga and
your body just needs that restoration so
listening to that
and i would i would come home from
school i remember this so vividly
and i thought like i would just flop on
my bed and be like
what i can't do anything what could i
even do right now
the temptation is just to go you know
smokeable and watch netflix and instead
it was just
okay roll out the map get some music
playing
except just have a you know take a hit
and it just moves through you
you just start moving and then like you
said before you know it
it's been an hour you're just flowing
and even if you don't
feel comfortable enough to
take yourself through a flow there are
so many free
amazing resources out there there are so
many resources and there's huge value
in having a teacher absolutely
especially if you have
you know certain areas that you really
want to work on or if you have
old injuries like please practice safely
and trust your body trust that
when you hear yourself saying oh that's
a little too
far listen to that and have that be part
of the learning
too because really yoga the simplest
definition of yoga
is to yoke to bring together the body
the mind and the spirit
and i think a lot of the pain a lot of
the struggle that we experience
is that splintering or the dissection
the body is way back here the mind is
way
there in the future and our spirit is
like what are we doing guys
yeah where are you i need you here
and yoga is so beautiful for bringing
that together
and then it's just a lovely it's a
lovely space to
embody uh those intentions that we hold
it's a great place to practice
self-compassion
right an understanding for yourself it's
a great way to
get stronger it's you know it's a great
way to work on your breath
there's so kind of so many endless
benefits that i can't recommend it
enough
yes and if like i said if if
having a j with you is the thing that
gets you into yoga
awesome
uh sorry it's this wonderful i always
again you know like i said before i had
um my preconceived ideas that weren't
super filled with information about like
religion or
christianity or like these important
wonderful words as
as a human that you can learn um i used
to have my saying like i had smoked weed
before just i was a skateboarder in high
school i would smoke weed um just
casually
but i was just over it and then after a
while i'd be like yeah i'm not a stoner
they're just losers blah blah and you
like
you you just kind of pick up this idea
about what it really is
then you forget of like all like the the
long shamanic traditions of plant
medicines and
like the the truth of what it really is
you know and
and what it can really be at for
individuals and i think that
when you can kind of kind of detach your
opinions on these sort of things or
detach your opinion on on weed for
example
um take it away from and this is just
uh for me personally to take it away
from
the social party aspect of it like it's
like don't see it as that like
me i started smoking by myself and i was
like oh i actually am able to slow down
and pay attention to these youtube
videos a little more
i'm actually able to slow down and like
not get mad at myself that i just spent
an hour stretching on the ground because
there's also this like need to like
oh what what am i doing or or we also
unfortunately i think we still see yoga
and these sorts of things as
well it's my workout today it's my how
many calories did i burn
what did i like like all these these
crazy things when
when just like focusing on the breath
where you and you notice your mind and
you get frustrated and you're
complaining and then you're like oh
there i am
complaining again that's what my mind's
doing okay back to the breath
yoga when you find your edges you don't
get mad at yourself or judge yourself
like oh i'm so not flexible oh that knee
hurts and i'm
never gonna have a good knee or whatever
it is you say oh that's where my body is
okay cool send some breath there let's
keep going you know
sound some breath send some love and
it's
i love what you said you know just
speaking
on plant medicine a little bit more you
know there was a time when
i was taking god it must have been
you know on certain times like around my
cycle for example to manage extreme
pain i was taking four
ibuprofen four times a day for like a
week
right that was prescribed to me and
what that was doing was ripping apart
the lining of my gut and
so to use cannabis as pain management
for that time
was so so helpful and i stopped i mean i
haven't taken ibuprofen in
in probably five or six years that's
crazy i
cause i used to take a ton of ibuprofen
just because i would i would just i
would
drink three times a week just uh it
wasn't like an
alcoholic didn't like ever get really
like once in a while i'd get hammered it
was just a casual thing
but i had this thing that was connected
to it where in the morning i just had
four ibuprofen right next to my bed it's
like well i drank last night and so what
i do when i drink is i
take the ibuprofen and you don't think
about these things i love that you said
gut lining too because i
um i haven't been to the doctor for it
but i've kind of deemed that i had that
issue
with a couple of um fitness friends and
i'm working on healing that i'm taking
collagen and these sort of things and
all my greens and i don't take any of
the ibuprofen anymore i haven't i
haven't for
a while i don't yeah that i mean i think
so many people can can benefit from that
um
totally okay so so tell me a little bit
more i know or sidetrack in a little bit
tell me a little bit more about plant
medicine so
i uh i it's definitely something on this
podcast that i like to explore i know
that
um some of it gets a little weird we're
like not sure how much we could say
um but i think that we live in a world
where that's you know
very soon to be changed and i think that
we're going to
be almost looking back in in future i
think we're going to look back at all
the time that we
treated as treated plant medicines as a
party drug or uh
like you see trippy stuff or whatever
like the weird stuff about it like
there's just
so much powerful i mean we're gonna
heal so many people with depression if
you've heard of any of the map stuff
or um yes yeah so okay give me give me a
little bit
definitely on the same vibe um give me
some of your experience with plant
medicine and if you don't mind
what was your did you have opinions on
it before you had tried it like did you
have bad annotations sorted or
oh my gosh okay so first of all i
you know when i was growing up and i
think this expression is hilarious so i
have to use it
we was like the devil's lettuce like we
was like
of the devil it was not like a healing
herb to be
you know to be used responsibly for
medicinal purposes
right it wasn't this you know that has
so
many incredible topical benefits
cbd you know there's so much there so i
definitely
had a huge stigma i never you know i
didn't
try anything until like probably mid
college any other any kind of drugs
other than alcohol
um was very super judgy
and i will own that i will own that i
was judging as [__]
and that's part of it you know what i
mean it's it's opening
it's being willing to see something
differently and
so you know there was a huge part of me
when i first moved to la so little
little backtrack that after houston i
just decided
i couldn't you know i couldn't keep
living that that was not my dharma
that was not the my highest contribution
i took this yoga teacher training with
uh
the woman that was trained by these
beautiful you know these beautiful
husband and wife who
ran this program and did work with
teachers and school counselors and
that totally opened up my world and the
day after my yoga teacher training i
moved out to
and that's when a lot of things shifted
and when i first moved there i started
teaching a lot of cannabis yoga
i taught at a cannabis yoga studio i you
know i taught private sessions with
small groups and it was so beautiful
to learn how to infuse intention
and meaning and love into every aspect
of that process
teach people about dosages to teach
people about
ratios and it really just like this
educational process and have it be
infused with intention
and it's so funny now because i
now will smoke weed and just a very
little bit
and we'll have like a psychedelic
experience seriously
it is really connects you to the divine
huh super it is like
directs connection so is that the only
way
of course not is that a way that
everyone needs to take
no and is it something that we dare not
overlook
should we ever get ourselves off of
so many prescription drugs yes we cannot
overlook it
and you know mushrooms mushrooms are a
whole other thing
this was you know i was probably
like i don't know early
mid yeah 22 something like that
when i first had an experience and it
was with a trusted person
this was you know it was at um
i remember one experience that i had
that was like in a very private
beautiful natural setting and
was just i found
that my my purest essence this is the
only way i can put it
my purest essence was just like
emanating like the sun
from me it was i was so
filled with wonder at a piece of fruit
something so simple like that right or
just
breathing outside right having that
experience being
so awe struck with the
miracle of existence is how i would put
it
and you know the other things that
people describe
like you know visuals and all those
things
to me that's just part of lifting the
veil
of illusion that is we see
you know this water bottle it's it it's
a material this is a matter right i'm
holding it in my hand
except not really right like
this doesn't exist to you you're seeing
it through this screen
this is just this you know mass of
vibrating subatomic particles
that are mostly space that change when i
observe it right and then you get into
this whole like quantum physics thing
which we can
which we can definitely go there too but
yeah i stumbled into a lot of those two
i love those
right but while we're still on
psychedelics
um you know i had some i had those early
experiences with
a person that you know i really trusted
and in some safe environments i also had
some
like you know not necessarily i was
never like
really into partying but you know i had
some experiences at like a music
festival or two
that were just beautiful that i found
myself
intrinsically connected to everyone and
everything
crying tears of joy feeling
feeling so utterly divine
and so clearly seeing the divinity in
everyone and everything around me
and that's the experience that i that i
wish that everyone could have
i don't think everyone needs to have it
in that way
and i think it's a really really really
special thing
so it's something that i've
you know i have worked on
on guiding folks through this experience
and holding that space so that
they have the opportunity to do it in a
safe way in a comfortable way have
everyone that i work with
meditate for a month beforehand not
consume any tobacco
or any alcohol or any other drugs for
that matter
and to get really in a clear
headspace you know i'm sure you've read
michael pollan's book how to change your
mind
a lot about the the psychedelic history
and journey that it's all about your
mindset
set and setting are kind of tenants
that as long as your setting is set up
as long as you're in the best mindset
possible that
it's really pretty much guaranteed to be
a beautiful
explorative journey and it's one that i
think is
is crucial and really really helpful
for as i said seeing the divinity
in everyone and everything yeah that's
that's so powerful i mean i
like just thinking of the future you
know if things really keep going the way
they're quick they seem to be quickly
going with these plant medicines you
know
they're doing great um things with with
mdma and people with
um uh post-traumatic stress disorder and
you know and this is just something it's
for everybody if you're a human with a
brain like it's not just for certain
types of people
um can you just this might be difficult
to describe but i'm just trying to think
of people who have never
who are still in the mode of like why i
never really even thought about
psychedelics i heard
that it's this thing over here and then
i just like never really thought about
it again and maybe they're feeling more
open-minded now
how could how could seeing the divinity
or seeing your like the true oneness of
this
uh how would that make you feel better
like how does that help with depression
and anxiety like how you know
i love that to me there's a couple of
ways
one way is that it lets you it lets you
get out of your own very limited
viewpoint so quite quite
physiologically it opens up new neural
pathways
and that's one of the most helpful
things for
getting off the rut that the train track
of depression and anxiety
right it's like such a familiar pathway
and that our brain has a natural pruning
process
and that when we don't use certain
branches or pathways
they get pruned right they get cut off
so this is this is a way to open
up some of those new neural pathways
and as we talked about with hope earlier
if you can see
that there's a better way and that
there's a couple of different ways
to get to that better place then
that will that will pull you forward i
truly believe that that can
shift the entire trajectory of
someone's life yes oh man that's that's
like a great example i
when you're talking about the neural
pathways too um i've used this example
before
and i think that i've just heard it so
i've repeated it but um thinking of just
as simple as sledding down a hill
like a blank it's snowed overnight and
the hill that you sled down you keep
just going down the same way
and that's kind of like been your life
that's you're digging this big old rut
and after a while you just like you're
to the point where the walls are really
high you got snow on either side you
just keep giving
and you're thinking the same thoughts
and you're having the same habits and
you're like i don't understand what
anybody's talking about like why
like you just kind of fall like any time
you get a little bit out you just kind
of fall back into that it seems like
so i think uh psychedelics are a lot of
these practices that that we've
discussed i think have
they allow you to just a few seconds of
you know if
it's not noticing that you're even
playing in the snow
and like what is snow like this really
wide thing at least helps you like peek
over the edge of that wall that you've
created from sledding there for so many
years
um thinking these these um you know
non thinking the same thoughts that are
not helpful
you know um i had at the beginning of my
of my journey i definitely had um
i mean i was i had like this spark
like i need to i need to fight this
nihilism like i need to give it like one
more
like because i was very suicidal i was
like i'm gonna like
like i i had pretty much unconsciously
decided like that's what's gonna happen
i just have to kind of figure out how
how it's gonna go down whatever and i
had this this
these moments of like dang it man what
is going on like i'm just i was sitting
here in this room
looking at the wall that's all the
writing on the wall is just like what
like why am i doing this what is
happening and
i think that you know i talk about that
but i think i was like
lucky to have that like whatever
happened in my life whatever like
divine will of something like at least
gave me a little bit of strength
to even though i it felt fake and it
felt fickle and it felt
um i felt like i was lying to myself but
i was like man
something isn't going right here like
this isn't i should want to live you
know i should want to
and so what was happening with me is i
was stuck in that divot and i had no
idea but i had
i was trying these different things i
started with cannabis i start you know
yoga meditation
writing everything journaling like you
mentioned and it was
you know it was a little bit even though
it felt fake even though it felt fickle
i was like yeah i feel kind of mostly
sad but i'm gonna give this thing a try
um it gave me a little bit of edge to
sneak up and look over that
that neural pathway you know that that
sled
line that i had made for so many years
so i think and that's again where hope
and faith come in just
even if it's just a couple days it feels
fake explore this stuff um or
if you if for in not feeling fake you
could take psychedelics and just rips
you right out of that sled thing so
you totally it's like what sled there
was never any snow
you thought you were a snow you
knucklehead you are snow
but yeah you are the snow everything
else is right it's all together
and and thank you for sharing that it's
so so powerful
because i feel that you know i was i was
actually writing on this yesterday i was
i was feeling a little scramble brain
and i said
oh shoot i haven't meditated today
meditate and then
not you know maybe probably 30 minutes
later just
pouring spiritual downloads which for me
those occur like just if i'm writing
it's like something is moving the pen
and i don't know what it is it's just
going going going right and it's
you know it's really this idea that
so much of what we perceive
in our lives it's just coming from this
really really limited
perspective and if we're willing to have
enough
faith or trust if that word is more
helpful to you
to to say you know what
i'm willing to admit that i don't know
everything if we're just
willing enough to admit that and say and
have enough faith
or trust to say i don't understand
everything and i don't know exactly how
this is gonna go then
that to me that's enough wiggle room
right there to
really break through to really break
some ground on like whatever
next path that it is you take and i love
you know
you're sharing about the same thoughts
again and again
we think somewhere between you know
experts say somewhere between 50 to 70
000 thoughts a day and that 90
of those thoughts are the same thoughts
the same
thoughts the same thing over and over
again i'm hungry
[__] this oh why can't i'm i feel tired
um what about this work work work right
gotta get it done
like
[Music]
just on repeat the tapes and so
to me it's no no wonder that we feel
like this
broken record on the track skipping and
skipping
it's just because we repeated a bunch of
things a bunch of times
and we as humans are blessed and cursed
with as i said before metacognition to
think about
how we think so can we try on
like it was a jacket a new idea and say
okay i'm gonna feel this out maybe it's
not totally my style
maybe it's not like every jacket that
i've had before
but maybe it's just different enough to
where
let's just see let's see how it goes and
that is
to me one of the most pivotal mental
shifts
that i made conscious thought shifts
on my journey was going from a space of
pretty much everything is out to get me
the world is against me
things don't work out for me that kind
of thing to
everything even the tough stuff even the
challenging stuff
is ultimately working out for my highest
good
everything is working out for me and to
shift
to that that reframes
every moment of every day it says
when you're late because you ran into
seven stoplights
it has you think automatically wow what
if that just saved me from getting into
this horrible wreck with that person who
sped through the intersection or what if
i just needed this extra moment
in the car to finish the song that i'm
jamming to or
something that you know things says from
the highly meaningful
and life-altering to the
very small and still potentially
life-altering
yeah that's so powerful synchronicities
that's where you can see him
i mean i i think just shifting into
i i like to talk about a simple example
that i had heard before
basically say you're an adult um you
have a young daughter and she's about to
turn 16 and you're like okay well i'm
going to look for her
a new car she's going to get her
driver's license and you're like she
wants a red honda civic that's all she
wants that's the car we're going to get
her
all of a sudden you're going to see a
red honda you're going to start seeing
red honda civics like maybe for sale
whereas before if you had never had the
thought or knew that your daughter
wanted red hot a civic
you you may have passed them every day
multiple times you know
um and i think that when you can when
you can flip your perspective
to i'm gonna i'm gonna find it
i'm gonna see it i know that this is
working out in my best interest you're
gonna start seeing these red honda
civics in your life of like
of oh that thing happened to me well
i'm i'm looking for it i'm drawing my
attention towards it so
i know that before maybe i would think
that this is a terrible thing maybe i
would think that this is the worst
thing ever and i'm the victim and and of
course this happens to me again and
again
or you could say okay this is this is
that thing that i know that i was
looking for
i was ready for it you know this i'm
laughing
so hard right now because the example
that i always use when i say
this is red honda civic i wonder if we
like heard
i feel like did somebody else say it or
do we just that and this is where i have
literally no idea because i
honestly i read so much i listen to
podcasts i have a lot of beautiful
brilliant friends too
i'm like did i hear this in a
conversation did did i just think this
and but i remember it because i was
talking to a friend of mine
and i said yeah like you know it would
be like if you
you started seeing red honda civics and
then you just start seeing them
everywhere
and at the end of the conversation he
goes you know what's hilarious about
this and i was like what
marcus and he goes i have a red hot
civic
it's so crazy like it's i i don't know i
mean as much as you like i wanna i
always wanna latch onto these things and
i'm like that must be
that thing i love this like optimism of
i'm okay with not knowing i like where
that's going i'm just gonna trust it and
continue following it like this
uh i don't know that's just incredible
that's so cool
like what what are the odds you know
well hey guys listeners look for your
red honda civic yeah
and the cool thing is and i love to
bring this in
because my approach is also very like
i call it heaven meets earth i think the
spiritual stuff you gotta
you gotta have a perspective on spirit
and the interconnectedness of of our
lives and the world
right and we're humans it would be silly
to deny that we are
human beings and so really to link this
we have a part of our brains it's right
at the brain stem that is the reticular
activating
system and what the reticular activating
system does
is it filters information just like our
eyeballs
right all day we see countless
images we hear countless things and what
the particular activating system does is
helps us determine
what is important because it's just too
that much to focus on
we can't focus on it all that would be
impossible we would explode
so what that helps us do is we start
noticing something noticing
for me it started with numbers right a
lot of people talk about numbers and
synchronicities
and now everywhere i go
four four four four fours three three
three three threes
one eleven eleven i let you know all the
just repeating numbers
that i see near constantly
every time i drive every you know when i
look at the clock
and some people say okay well that's
great you see repeating numbers you
train your reticular activating system
to notice repeating numbers well what
does that mean
and this is where i think a lot of
people they
and you know no no fault in this jump to
google
right and say what does it mean when i
see this right without
first and this is what i would recommend
looking inward and saying
what do i feel like this is trying to
say and to me
those repeating numbers tell me a few
things
the world is full of patterns some of
those patterns
are downward spirals right and the
biggest down and some of those patterns
are upward spirals and lift us up
right and then also to me these
repeating numbers
i choose and feel deeply that they mean
for me
you're on the right path the timing is
working out
trust the timing of your life it's
always
working out for you and that didn't come
from
anything that i looked up on the
internet that came from me
introspecting and really sitting with it
and feeling
okay i'm seeing this everywhere what is
this
what does this mean for me yes that's so
important i really like that you ask
yourself that you're like
because i've even done that myself you
watch youtube videos or whatever and you
end up googling you're like oh it means
that your angel is watching over you and
like
you know a lot of that is great and a
lot of it lines up with certain people's
beliefs and it just like clicks to them
that's so great but uh i really believe
i always say
you give things power um i think i said
that earlier even but
like that's kind of how it is for me i
believe too when i see
number synchronicities which i see all
the time now to me
it's not that that google like i don't
go like oh it's the
you know whatever like three through
three means this i literally go
uh it's some sort of like everything is
going to be okay
like whatever's going on going on it's
gonna be okay
and uh it's cool i actually used to
write and i do still sometimes
depending on what i'm going through i'll
write little notes to myself on my hand
all right
everything is okay or i used to be
i used to be actually overly analytical
myself i was like i would write like
talk slower or things like that you know
i kind of flipped it to be like a little
more positive but
um uh but i it's just like that like
you know when you see imagine you're
having a bad day just like i think a lot
of the reason why people get tattoos and
stuff too you know you're having a bad
day and
like oh i'm all caught up in all this
thing and then you see your tattoo that
just says love yourself
and you're like oh yeah everything's
okay love yourself even though this is
going on
that's true cool it's happening but
love yourself or everything will be okay
or just be here whatever it is
when you see like the synchronicities
the numbers the red honda civics
it could be those everything is okay oh
yeah
i just remembered i mean imagine how how
much better you're gonna feel instead of
all those 70 how many thoughts a day do
we have fifty thousand seventy thousand
seventy million whatever
somewhere in there fifty to seventy
thousand it's a lot so
i mean think about like in all the
repeating thoughts that are just
saying that you're unworthy and you're
not you can't do this thing and like
yeah i don't really think that thought
anymore that's kind of a silly thing
whatever i mean
what if you inserted at least a few
times a day
where you see something on your hand or
you see a number that matches up
and it kind of replaces one of those
thoughts it says everything's going to
be okay it's just
it's almost like a wake up call
throughout your day you know
and you know with us of course lately
spending a lot more time in our homes
you know i i like to say that your home
is kind of like your vision board
surround yourself with the symbols that
are meaningful to you
surround yourself you know i have a lot
of times
clients put sticky notes or write on
their mirror just
you know a lot of us first thought when
we look in the mirror is like
not good right you lean that way
so this is part of the balance is saying
what if just
first i thought damn damn girl
or like i love my body i'm thankful for
my body
right something like that noticing what
and appreciating ourselves and from that
space
that's what allows us to notice and
appreciate and honestly
not judge and criticize other people
because if you're criticizing yourself
for something if you're hard on yourself
for something odds are
you're criticizing you're judging other
people whether verbally or not
and that is also it's kind of eroding
your compassion
right that self-compassion that we have
feeds our compassion for other people
our ability to empathize
our ability to see other people through
loving
eyes and trust that they
as hard as it might be to believe
sometimes are doing the best
with what they have at this time yes
yeah they're this is just like you my
friend as far as you know right now this
is your first time doing this life
situation
like a you know just like them they're
just trying to figure this out too
i wish that we could all like just have
this one moment
this like fairy tale in my head is just
like everybody's like oh yeah we just
remembered that we
all were were thinking that each other
said we were perfect
like nobody is walking around saying
that they're perfectly have it all
figured out i mean some people are sure
but
the for the most part everyone's just
kind of stumbling through this thing
trying to figure it out in the same way
as you are
and when you could remember that it's
like oh yeah what i was thinking about
isn't as important or
my judgments are i can let those go and
i could see this person
not through my judgments but through who
they really are you know
yeah i i dream of that i dream of that
the moment the collective moment when we
just all decide
to have a little bit more grace for
ourselves
i feel just the energy of
you know maybe it's maybe i've just been
spending a little too much time online
or something but this like
this wanting to just like jump down each
other's throats like
for every little thing and it feels like
have we just lost all sense of
compassion and grace for each other
and and because the genesis of that is
losing compassion and grace for
ourselves knowing that
part of the human experience and this is
what i believe and this is
i believe a healthy way to frame our
existence
is that humans are not broken
humans part of humanness
is humanness is [__] things up is
choosing things for the short term
payoff instead of the long term
or you know is part of humanness is
having an ego
and and battling with that and so i
think that when we
when we choose to remember that we are
whole we are whole beings and that
perfection was
never like you said part of the equation
that was never
a guarantee of that life
it's silly it's so silly yeah i i love
it you just said that i actually had i
had a quote that i had taken from
i did an instagram dive before this you
said you are not something broken to be
fixed
you are a garden to be tended to i
really like that that stood out and
you mentioned ego with that as well um i
i had heard this thing that
this reminded me of is the ego doesn't
want to be
destroyed it wants to be held and i was
like oh that's helpful because i went
through this time once i discovered like
how much my ego was running my life and
what it was and i was like oh my god
dude i have got to be
i've got to get rid of my ego i got to
destroy it i've gotta like
you know i'm trying to stomp out this
thing that i didn't understand yet and
now it's like
oh okay it's just a part of this
experience like you can
you can hold it and you could like you
you can almost like teach your ego
how to i mean it'll still it's not
always under your control in a sense
it's hard to conceptualize your ego as
it's like this separate being thing or
something but
um yeah i just really like how uh how
you put
you are a garden to be tended to you're
not something broken to be fixed
yeah it's okay you would never say like
oh
this is the perfect garden right gardens
are different
in different climates there's different
things that grow
more naturally right so you know some
plants need a little bit more water some
plants need a little bit more
sun there's and if you saw i imagine
this if you saw
a perfectly manicured trimmed
down to the tea garden it might not be
the most beautiful
it might not be you know hospitable to
the plants and animals that allow it to
truly
thrive right i mean all gardens need a
little bit of
weeding need a little bit of pruning
like i described that internal
brain pruning process that happens
naturally
that part of the you know
certain plants blooming in in
certain times and seasons right
teaches us there's a time for everything
i just love
i love the garden metaphor because it's
really
you know there were some seeds planted
in all of our gardens
that we never we never chose and
if that's grown and we've watered that
thought or
idea or construction or concept
that yeah we might have to do a little
bit of digging and
tilling of the earth really yes
love it and that's what i love to do
that's what i love to do with people is
reflect to them
okay it's okay if you didn't choose this
belief
a lot of us didn't choose our beliefs
yeah
we just believed we saw their gardens
around us and said oh this is the way
the gardens are around me
and so really just taking the time to
actually get to the root
which means getting your hand it's a
messy process nothing in life is like
perfectly ordered it's such an illusion
it's such
[__] it's harmful and toxic to us
that
you know digging in the earth uprooting
that and seeing okay now from this
place what do i choose to plant here
what are the thoughts what are the ideas
that i choose
to nourish and water you know every
single day
or or check on every single day make
sure they're getting the right
sunlight right the right light and
energy
poured into them oh if there's an
infestation how do i handle that how do
i bring
balance to the entire ecosystem
and you we're seeing this on a very
collective level that
in many areas basically there you know
there have been certain kinds of
plants that have been destroyed which
means this certain population
of animal can't eat which means that
this other population of animal because
they can't eat
they don't have enough to eat or they
have too much to eat so they're
overpopulated right and it's it's seeing
that
it's not separate and that like this is
kind of going on an ecological level now
but
seeing seeing ourselves as separate from
the environment is our biggest
downfall ooh tell me more keep going now
we are
one and the same with it that it is
it's just as silly to say something like
you know the environment
well that's we're fooling ourselves it's
us
we are the environment how do we breathe
right now without the trees get rid of
all the trees how are we going to
breathe
this is our this is our garden and then
it's like the garden
of the collective consciousness right
garden of the earth
includes the plants and the animals yes
right and all of you know i think about
bees
a lot for example like bees have
stingers because they need to survive
and a lot of them i can speak from
experience have had a bee
one time i just had this bee like crawl
around me for like
five minutes seriously it was just on me
if i just just checking things out
and without bees like okay well there
goes all our food
there goes seventy percent of the
world's
food in bees this tiny thing that we get
like annoyed by
right or we're like afraid of or
whatever we need we need to protect
ourselves from it put up a blockade and
like oh attack it or kill it or whatever
i mean i i'm guilty of that too i don't
want to be hanging out with a bee but i
am slowly getting to where i'm not
uncomfortable by insects
oh it's a journey you start to see like
who's
who's left with the disgust and the fear
when you're like oh this thing
once again easier said than done i
haven't gotten to the like
picking up the cockroach level but i
have really
really worked on not jumping to
i need to destroy this thing which used
to be it which is like such a silly
fear not that there aren't animals that
could potentially harm us of course
that's
right possibility you you could
literally just be like oh okay well
there's that spider doing the thing that
spiders do i'm gonna just continue doing
the thing that humans do
i'm gonna human while he spiders you
know like it's so simple
but uh yeah it's it's such a fun journey
to learn i
so the um the oneness of
everything of course you know studying
any sort of like hinduism or or buddhism
or any of those
um or i'm not sure exactly that hinduism
points out a ton i haven't studied a lot
of hinduism but
um essentially like really
understanding conceptualizing like the
we are one you know
there are certain meditative states that
you can experience this
um but i had strangely enough just on
netflix there's this documentary called
one strange rock with will smith have
you seen that one
is it an episode or is it one whole
thing i think it's episodes it's
episodes
okay i've seen i think i've seen an
episode or two because you better
believe that as my
those kind of things are my [__] yes i'd
love a good documentary
nowadays we have such great ability to
make fantastic documentaries but um
the the first episode was i think that
was like my favorite but i remember like
they were really describing like the
breakdown of like here's how
air works and here's how uh like the
diatoms are formed
that that make the water and it forms it
like it and you're just like
oh my god what like it
it's that thing where like we were
talking about earlier what makes you
feel small
and then it's almost you almost have
this laughing moment of like holy crap
like why isn't this the most known thing
ever of course there's a lot of new
science and they're able to explain it
better and now
you know they have a famous actor will
smith who's like we can connect with a
little bit more maybe it's better
language or more casual so
uh yeah anybody who hasn't seen one
strange rock on netflix if you want to
understand like
when we're saying like we are one and
this this whole thing we're in is
connected you know
anna was talking about the difference
between like we we separate our
environment like it's something
that's over there has nothing to do with
us and should we focus on it should we
fix it should we work on our environment
it's like
uh it's us it's what we it's like how we
do this
so we should you know like yeah um i i
wanted to ask you a little bit about
your
um so we kind of left off on you you had
gone
to la um you were starting this journey
um but you've been
a coach and a yoga instructor now for a
while um
i mean like tell me about some of that
what have been your experiences how how
have people been doing
um since the quarantine even like how
has your practice changed since the
quarantine
um and then also just because i don't
want to forget before the end of this at
any time or no rush we've got plane time
but um if you have like your own videos
and your own
youtube channel your own site make sure
we can get to like watch your yoga
videos and learn from you more because i
want to make sure
that's out there 100 so
really when i first i described it kind
of this when i first moved to la
i was a lot of my healing happened
in the physical body of course it's all
tied in right it's not separate
however yoga i was like i just want to
help people feel better in their bodies
people are so uncomfortable in their own
skin
you know they feel like something's
always wrong or if they have
pain it's pain is very root chakra
right it's very difficult to
to elevate levels of consciousness if
you are
in constant pain pain will keep you
really stuck
in and for anyone who you know who's
listening you're like i don't know
about chakras root chakra really
represents
kind of survival and base level security
you can also kind of compare it to like
maslow's hierarchy
of needs which is the base level which
is
survival right so if you're in survival
mode it's really difficult
to contemplate things like
self-actualization
right and self-awareness it's so
grandiose and you're just like i
my back hurts every day right right so
i really wanted to help people with that
i was teaching a ton
of yoga and as i think is a really
i think it's a really smart move when
you're kind of starting on your own
business or
or you're doing the entrepreneur thing
is not to just like shift over all your
chips at once
right so i had a couple of different
things
going on i wasn't just teaching yoga at
this point and that was a lot of what i
was doing
so i had you know a couple of other
things supplemental income this kind of
stuff
and really loved it and quickly
discovered
that it is pretty tough to teach like 16
yoga classes in a week
you think that that i don't know maybe
you think that sounds like a ton
it is a time it's a lot you're driving
around you're planning out your
sequences you're making playlists
you're catering to you know all
different kinds of audiences and
experiences and you know
it's it's just a lot so i i started to
get more into meditation i'm so thankful
i was
actually working the front desk at a
yoga studio that i taught at
and i loved this place it was it was so
nurturing to me it opened
up right around my birthday
a couple of months after i moved to la
and it was a mile from my house it was
like the god said i was like this
is the place and at that place when i
was at the front desk you know there are
hours that go by without anyone coming
you know
walking in so i would read and i would
read
all of the books that they had
incredible
incredible books one that i can't
recommend enough if you feel like you've
got trauma stored in your body which all
of us
pretty much all of us do is the body
keeps the score
i was hoping you were saying that book
yeah i have i have that and maslow
hierarchy and needs like six feet away
from me so
i makes me so happy i feel like i've
given
i've so many times bought copies and
then just given them away right away
that i don't even know if i have a copy
right now i'm like i think it's
somewhere i don't know
bless people who do that by the way
that's like the best trait to give
people books
i when people give me a book i'm like oh
my god like that's
you like okay it's meant i'm meant to
read this i'm like i'm about to send you
a book
or like three books it is my favorite
thing it's like the spreading
you know spreading and cultivation of
knowledge and awareness it's planting
new seeds
people's garden and it's like hey try on
this plant this plant like
really let the daylilies blossom you
know um
so after as i was doing that you know it
was i
was working still a lot i was leading
online coaching programs and this whole
time i'm being coached and mentored in
coaching
i took my meditation teacher training
with this amazing amazing man named
david nicktern
also at the yoga studio they brought him
there
and it really it just started to open up
so much for me i learned more about
buddhism
i would highly recommend uh the wisdom
of no escape by pema children
also a beautiful beautiful book
meditation maybe that's the one i'll
said you
and it's um it's perspectives
on how really how to live
meditation right off the cushion it's
like
what what is meditation and motion in
your life
daily look like practicing cultivating
loving kindness and compassion right or
or noting the breath noting your
thoughts and
judgments as they surface and all
of that it just it got me meditating
really consistently
doing that program i started meditating
and i this is a great
you know a great place to be is you know
20 minutes
five times a week is a beautiful
meditation routine
that's like i think it's pretty doable
and even if you have to break it up
10 minutes twice a day five times a week
do it if you have to be lying down if
you want to be sitting up if you want to
be walking
like just do it but have that be the
dedicated time
and that really it opened up so much
spiritually for me i started to
you know learn more about just the fun
other elements of spirituality
like cards my friend uh actually at this
yoga studio this yoga studio is like
just the epicenter of so much of my like
quantum leaps
in la because there was you know there
was different kinds of people that were
we had yoga pilates and meditation and
so these pilates teachers there was a
older woman who gifted me this this
deck of cards called the medicine cards
and it's all about the lessons of
animals and
taken from native american folklore that
really teach us and give us medicine
for how to live how to connect to spirit
in all things how to see
the lessons of the aunt as just as
valuable as the lessons of the panther
right something like that so that was a
whole
other element that opened up for me was
seeing how
along my path that animals have always
been communicating
with me and sending me spiritual
messages that was
so fun and so wild to open up to and and
that played an
element and i discovered that you know
as i was learning to
coach and i had always had like the
coaching teaching perspective
right like when i was in college i was a
writing coach and would coach people
through academic goals
so i've always been really attuned to
that
and the way that i was leading programs
and working with my mentors and coaches
was
a very masculine way was very
linear very goal-centric
uh very kind of structured and that is
really
really helpful it's really helpful thing
it's gotten our society very far
it's it's helped us gain a lot of ground
and as all beings are we need that
balance
of the more masculine energy and the
feminine energy
so i started to lean more into my
intuition
and i started to open up to different
practices like
ecstatic dance and ceremony and ritual
and and just discovering that powerful
feminine energy as well
along with that manifestation reading
every book i
get my hands on taking all the courses
like just
soaking up so much rich learning because
now i had time and energy to do that
and it just blew my mind that i can make
my schedule for the day and that i can
plan my business
around the different phases of my cycle
and when i'm in a really extra intuitive
space i can do
big picture visioning and you know when
i'm on my moon cycle
i can take days at a time to rest like i
really need
right right and learn to work with
my body learn to work with the things
that i love to do so
what i've seen in that time is
incredible
i've had clients who have completely
healed themselves from autoimmune
disorders
i've had um you know folks who have
grappled with
non-epileptic seizures through
mindfulness
discover a dramatic decrease in
their seizures and their ability to just
live day to day so awesome
i've you know so there's like that whole
spectrum
and then now you know i've been leading
mindful living mentorship
a program that i run for about a year
and just seeing
how really simple commitments
and to your body to your mind and to
your spirit
the accountability to meditate on a
daily or at least
multiple times weekly basis brings
so much more ease right i think we focus
a lot on like reducing stress
i'm like no i want to bring ease to your
life i want to bring
joy to your life and nurture that and
the stress will just melt
away that will happen
so what i've really seen you know during
quarantine like right before quarantine
it was such an interesting time
i lost kind of two of my biggest
sources of income so the yoga studio
that i was teaching at closed
which was really really sad
and and i think a necessary
loss necessary part of the process after
completing
and a meditation plan i would go and
lead meditation at this office
and um they too the business was
struggling so they were feeling all of
these
impacts of coven and on the economy and
whatnot
and i i really thought to myself you
know i've been doing this thing for a
while i've been
i've been coaching i have been loving
serving my private clients i've been
creating programs
i think at this point i could really use
a business coach
and i stumbled upon this woman
she was pretty much one day away from
starting
this six month mastermind and this was
started at the very beginning of march i
had never
invested this much in a program like
this for myself for my business no less
and it was terrifying it was one of
those
terrifying growth steps you're like i
know i need to do this but this is still
really scary but i know i need to do
this
it's like good fear and i know like we
have all felt that
of the next step because it's growth so
what i discovered in that process was i
really i wanted just to learn how can i
continue to serve
better how can i serve my clients better
how can i make this
this business when i'm working on
sustainable and scalable and
and eventually employ people and
support you know a network of people
that are
that want to live an aligned and soulful
and beautiful life and
that that's exactly what happened i
started
um i remember i started around like
right at the beginning of quarantine i
felt like
usually i'll have like a month or two in
between those programs and this was like
two weeks and i was like you guys i
don't care
we need this now like let's do this and
what i discovered was that people
were really really receptive
people were really open to
taking a leap and and trusting
themselves to say i know what i need
and honestly i need some community i
need some support
and i need some structure i needed
something to support me to hold me up
and that's what that program was and to
hear people say like
i managed the quarantine and everything
that came with it
so much better as a result of this
as a result of like some of the simplest
tools i really believe in making it
simple for people it doesn't have to be
complicated breath work meditation
reflection journals is like what it is
pretty much
and it's it's just the best thing in the
whole world
it's like it's the thing that gets me
like leave out of bed in the morning
and now i just started this
basically now i'm leaving a six-month
mastermind for
six women oh you know for to
who really like my intention was like a
lot of people are like i'm
over 2020 right people are like done
with you and i'm like
boo it's it's certainly not over like
in a way it feels like we're just
getting started so i really wanted
a container a space for for people who
these are a lot of people have been in
work with me to continue to grow
and you know it's called soul shine
social and masculine it's bringing your
fullest
self every single day to uplift
everyone around you and a lot of these
women there are
you know they've studied functional
medicine or they're health coaches or
some of them are yoga teachers
and then and then some of them are just
people who have discovered and seen this
work work for themselves
and they want to know how to go deeper
how can i more
fully live in my purpose how can i
have more fun or feel more confident in
sharing the things that i know have
helped me and that can probably help
other people
so that's like between that and moving
to joshua tree and we haven't even
talked about this but i also
um well i won't say met we met about a
year ago when we're best friends but
i'm now with my absolute soulmate twin
flame
love of my life that all happened in
quarantine
so i'm over here sitting like this is my
this is the best year ever
i have like no hatred no qualm with 20
20.
and acknowledge it's brought up a lot of
painful
stuff it's we like asked for clarity and
we got it and
clarity is can be tough sometimes the
illusion
the veil being removed can be painful
it's like
blinking your eyes at the at the bright
sunlight
yeah tell me about it i uh you know we
all have our our dark knights of the
soul
that we experience in strange ways and
and uh a lot of the
shadow work you know brings up these
things in different ways um
man that's a your story is just so great
anna
uh just thinking about like so
so thinking about what we have now you
know with technology
like the ability to really like even
doing this you know like you're in
joshua tree right now
and yeah like it's this bummer thing
that
quarantine happened and like we're not
able to like people can't meet in person
i can't do as many in-person podcasts
and
all these things but we also are able to
do these sort of things more and we're
also able to do
you know when it comes to healing and
healing our mind there's so many
different things we can do and we can
find it online we can find it on our
computers we can
like master classes and and um and and
like these these uh retreats and stuff
and the masterminds that you do
like that's something that is kind of
new like in the last
you know we people have been doing them
for probably 10 years or something i'm
sure but
it seems like in the last five years you
see just different levels of them i see
tony haw like nowadays you can go online
masterclass.com tony hawk teaches you
how to skateboard
or the uh i'm spacing his name
the the famous chef who's like kind of
an [__] but he's like a really good
jordan ramsey gordon ramsay he has his
own master class like you can literally
just learn
directly from people like they don't
have to have grown up in your same
community you don't have to they don't
have to be a family friend you know like
you could
just be drawn to these certain ways of
learning and you can learn in different
ways so
what um could you just explain to me
for imagine that the person has like
they haven't heard of a master class or
a mastermind
or any of this like so um
like don't give away all your juice of
course but like like what exactly do
do they do and and how does that benefit
them day-to-day
yeah absolutely so to me if
there's kind of two ways that we
grow right growth is part of is part of
us naturally
we are made for growth expansion
learning
right now it's a lot easier like you
said
with so much technology with so much
knowledge
widely available right
i believe that there's two ways you can
go
you can grow like no coming to
consciousness except through pain
like like the universe whispers is like
hey
you've been stuck in this situation for
a long time like maybe it's time to move
on
come on like they kind of like give you
nudges
and then it's like hey wake up right and
then it becomes louder and more
uncomfortable
so we can grow through that way and i
chose that way for a long time
unconsciously chose it because i didn't
know there was another way there's
another way that we can grow and that is
growing through joy to me the elements
of growing through joy
are that you have a container for a
specified amount of time
right we it's too much for us like
talking about like
you know grid and like long-term goals
like
it's we get really demoralized when it's
way too far in the future
if it's like five years right or or
three years
and that's why you know a lot of
programs like mindful living mentorship
is seven weeks it's seven weeks because
that's about
the time it takes to really instill a
habit
right soul shine it's six months because
i really wanted something
longer term and sustained like what i
had experienced which is
compound interest of growth growth over
time
just like you know dollars in the bank
you see what little deposits each day
there and huge huge harvest huge rewards
right that sustained commitment and then
also making sure that your growth
is sustainable that it's not um i will
never promise anyone
a quick fix a magic pill like this
is if you want that i that this is not
the thing for you
right yeah it's gonna be working i
really believe that
it doesn't have to be struggle bus right
it doesn't have you don't have to be the
victim
you don't need a victim's story to grow
and learn
but that really if you desire to grow
and you want to grow in joy
choose something that's going to be a
little bit uncomfortable like
this program where basically i teach you
all of the things that i have done over
the last couple of years
so that this year has gone how it's gone
for me
right so really practically how to deal
with your doubt and your fear we work on
unmapping and unwiring or unlearning
triggers and conditioning and then how
to consciously
that's funny how to consciously program
your subconscious
how to program beliefs so that
those are the beliefs that you choose
right for yourself to cultivate a life
that you see
and then also how to live from a
centered and aligned place
so that everything that you're doing
from the daily micro
to the macro to the big actions and the
big leaps
are in alignment with what your soul
values
not what the world says you need not
what your ego wants but what truly your
soul space
is here to bring you've maybe heard it
as your dharma
or your purpose right your life's
mission
all those things aligning with that i
also teach very practically
my process which is you know bits
from abraham hicks and bits from joe
dispenza
and science and spirituality and just my
own experimentation and exploration
to learn how to consistently and
confidently
manifest and create a reality that you
are in love with yeah so that's really
what that's about
that's incredible i mean yeah that's
perfect i i love
i love that you had a chance to explain
it because it's we can
really see it as like something new and
something um
special like it really is is like this
cool opportunity that we have
like nowadays you know i was talking
about sam harris's waking up app
like we oh my gosh like if this was the
60s i would have had to
all right well i gotta quit my life and
i gotta go to the tibet
and i gotta go across the mountains and
i gotta say the right passwords so they
don't say like oh the guru is not home
and
and like and i gotta work there for six
months and then maybe he's actually been
here the whole time and i didn't know it
was him and
all these like you know like you we've
heard these enlightenment stories of
going going to the mountain and
now like we have advanced so much and
we're like we can help each other in
such
incredible ways we can speak each
other's language too and really connect
on like where we're actually at
and i mean technology is is quite the
thing
um it's it's painful in a lot of ways i
just watched the social dilemma on
netflix last night which is a
oh man that was like hard to watch um
which i recommend if anybody should
watch that you should definitely watch
it um but
um or or that sorry that listener should
watch it um
and but i think that we also can see
these things as
wonderful powerful tools as individuals
for you know
i mean the fact that you can connect
with someone through
this through the laptop you know through
through a camera or through
phone calls or you can you have access
to so much more than we used to have
just
you know 40 years ago 30 years ago 20
years ago uh
i think it's it's so great i think it's
really cool that you're doing what
you're doing too
and i think that um like
you you've really shifted your life and
experienced these things and always been
kind of like
looking for it seems like you're just
looking for like different ways to serve
and that's just a beautiful thing and
the the most beautiful thing
is that it's full circle like it gives
you a good life
like you know like you can you can live
through service instead of like what can
i get
and then once i get enough and i have
enough extra money and i don't want any
more ferraris then i could donate some
money to charity it's like
no no you could start and you could how
can i serve other people and like
life just starts sprinkling some stuff
on you and it's like here's how you can
serve
and you're going to love yourself for it
you know oh my god
that's to me that's the it's such an
impactful way to live
through the lens of every single day i
meditate and i ask myself and not my ego
i ask my the deepest part of myself
how can i serve how can i contribute to
the world today
and a lot of times you know the message
the message is just share your story
and and give people that hope and that
trust that you know what
this person you see right now
unrecognizable
from years ago from like i always say
it's like my
hot mess stressed anxious depressed anna
was like then and like unrecognizable
from the woman that you see before you
so if you're feeling like god there's
just
no way that i could see this getting
better for myself like i really just
if there's anything that i can say is it
can and will get better
choose choose to look for the good
choose to see what you can learn from
the tough stuff
and know that change is is life life has
changed and changes life
like that's just all part of it 100
okay anna we're getting up here in time
this has been such a wonderful
conversation
uh i'm super i'm so grateful for chase
that chase is just such an awesome
person anyway he's like so inspiring and
anytime i got to work with him i was
like this guy is impressive
um but i'm so glad that he connected us
so glad we had got we got to have this
conversation um
give me just uh one more time before we
send it off here
give the listeners where can they find
you what's your instagram handle
uh what website you have a website up
yet i do yeah absolutely
so um thankfully it's all all condensed
and streamlined
my website is www.annacantwell.com
that's
a-n-n-a-c-a-n-t-w-e-l-l
my instagram is probably where i most
active it's i
am anna cantwell super simple and then
that'll have links to my website
i have a facebook community where i lead
live meditations every week
and in the works in the process
is a membership where i'll have all my
yoga videos all my meditations
and then all this fun energetic
spiritual stuff too
that'll be available super super soon
and i have also a round of mindful
living mentorship
it's coming up and it will start on
september 27th
you can take it from anywhere in the
world it's all over
zoom we meet for an hour 15 once a week
for
seven weeks it'll bring you right up to
right before
uh thanksgiving just like the week or
two before
so if you're looking for some
consistency
and some community those are the two
really three promises clarity
you're looking for some of that that's a
great place to start
to get into meditation to build these
habits that
support you living just a wonderful life
and thank you
thank you so much jay for having me and
thank you all for listening
yeah this is so great this is super cool
anna um
well listeners take care of yourself uh
i'm gonna end this recording but and i
will talk for another couple minutes but
uh
listeners drink water stretch don't be
afraid to
to challenge your own beliefs and and
explore yourself like
you're here and that's okay you could
just figure this life out and you could
live you could live a life where you
love yourself every day it's clearly
possible like
it's there's so many people popping up
like anna who are just like hey
trust me here i'm live i'm happy and you
can be too
and i think that when you hear people
share their story like that it really
sparks this thing within each each of us
as individuals where we're like maybe i
can
maybe i can do it and hey listen
listener you can love yourself
all right peace out have a good day
[Music]
listeners
my
knowledge is power
[Music]
you